Lloyd: So now that you've completed
session three ,it's time to complete
section three in the assessment booklet.
So if you open your assessment
booklet and scroll down to section
three, this is about understanding
what is meant by social engineering.
Now, one of the key points to take
note of in this section, in this
section only is that for the learning
outcomes 3.1 to 3.6, you've got to
use a real world instance of social
engineering to meet the requirements.
So, as as indicated here, you could
do this by looking at a friend, family
member or work colleague's social media
accounts to identify information that
could potentially be used to carry
out social engineering on their peers.
Alternatively, you may want to
carry out a search to gather
information about a business or an
individual that could be used to
design a social engineering attack.
So the option is there for you.
But you've got obviously the learning
objectives and the questions where
that information can be found in
the course materials to assist you.
So if you scroll down to question 1,
in the box below it's asking you to
define the term social engineering
and give an example of how it is used.
So what is social engineering
and how is it used?
For question 2 it's asking you, can
you think about an instance when you
are targeted by a cyber criminal?
This could have been via telephone,
email, or text/instant messaging.
Alternatively, you may use the
experience of a family member, friend,
or an example that you've read about.
So you've got to have an
example and explain the type
of attack and what happened.
So what was the type of
attack and what happened?
What was the outcome?
For question 2B, it's asking you
to explain what the cyber criminal
was hoping to achieve from the
attacks or what was the purpose?
What did they want to
get from that attack?
And then for 2C, explain what benefits
that the social engineer in methods used
in the attack were for the cyber criminal.
So looking at the methods that were
used for the attack, what were the
benefits to the cyber criminal of
using those social engineering methods?
For question 3A, it's asking
you to describe what is meant
by open source information.
And then for question 3B, it's asking
you to identify the different types of
information that you could obtain through
open source information about friends,
family members, or work colleagues.
You need to give three examples.
So think about the different types
of information that you can find
out about your friends, family
members, and work colleagues.
For question 4A, it's asking you in
the box below, identify the different
types of information that the cyber
criminal could obtain using open sources.
So the various open source platforms out
there, what sort of information can a
cyber criminal obtain looking at those?
For question 4B, using social media,
look up a friend, family member or
colleague and describe the information
that the say cyber criminal could obtain
about that person in the box below.
So think about the information
that's out there and what information
could a cyber criminal obtain?
For questions 5, in the box below describe
the different techniques that could
be used as part of social engineering.
So what are the techniques
that could be used?
So the different things that you've
covered in the course materials, what
are they and what are the different
ways that they it can be used?
And then for 5B, using the information
that you've obtained, so your research
conducted in this section so far, so
all of the information that you've
gathered all the way through from
questions 1 to 5A, in 5B, it's asking
you to provide a description of the
techniques that the cyber criminal
could use to carry out an attack on your
friends, family members, or colleagues.
And the final question in this section,
it's asking you to evaluate the
information that you've gathered and
in the box below, identify the useful
information that a cyber criminal
could obtain by conducting a social
engineering attack on one or more of
the people that you have researched.
Once you've done that, if you can
then read through your answers, and
once you're happy with them, carry
out a spelling and grammar check,
save the document, and then you can
submit that to your tutor for marking.